無賴！
Scoundrel!
你應該提前告訴我們的
You should have atleast told us.
告訴你什麼？
Told you what?
祝你生日快樂，瓦伊巴夫
Best wishes on your birthday, Vaibhav.
我永遠不會忘記我們第一次見麵的情景
I will never forget the first time we met.
你站在走廊裏又餓又渴，而我..
You were standing there hungry and thirsty in the corridor and I..
-不是…… -聽我說完
It's not.. - Let me complete.
第一眼看到你，我就覺得我在前往計算機科學的旅程中
At first sight I felt I'd found my companion..
找到了同伴
..on the journey to IT Bombay Computer science.
米納，今天不是我的生日
Meena, it is not my birthday.
你們有錢人隨時都可以吃蛋糕嗎？
Do you rich people eat cake whenever you want?
我去馬赫什瓦裏看了瓦蒂卡的考試成績
I went to Maheshwari to check on Vartika's results.
路上碰到一家蛋糕店，所以我就買了一個蛋糕
I came across a bakery on the way so, I bought a cake.
如果我告訴她這個好消息，她會很高興的
She would be happy when I'd tell her the good news.
她會稱贊我，讓我覺得自己是個英雄
She would give me credit. I will feel like a hero.
然後你就可以親她了
And you will get to kiss her.
對吧，兄弟? 一定是這樣，然後呢？
Right, bro? You were right. Then?
然後……我看到成績了
What then? I saw the results.
瓦蒂卡冇考過，我過了
Vartika didn't make it. I did.
你仔細看成績單了嗎？
Did you check the results thoroughly?
我從上到下看了八遍
Eight times. From up to down.
你教了她那麼多，但她還是冇通過？
You taught her so much, bro, and yet she didn't make it?
她可真笨
She's a very dumb girl..
不過很適合做女朋友
..but good choice for girlfriend.
不，很多同學都參加了考試
No. Many students sat for the exam. Somesh. Shubham.
阿洛克，尤察夫，他們的名字都在名單上
Alok. Utsav. All their names were on the list.
-我們班的尤察夫?-是的
Our Shubham? - Yes.
馬赫什瓦裏這批隻招80人
Maheshwari has batches of 80 students.
如果招200人，那瓦蒂卡才能通過
If they had batches of 200 students then Vartika would have made it.
你在哪個組?-A3
Which batch did you get? - A3.
太好了! 如果老師都冇能進入第一組
Great! When the teacher didn't make it to the first batch..
他怎麼能指望他的學生進去呢？
..how can he expect his student to get selected?
你就像巴特拉
You are just like Batla.
-嘿! 就連佈吉揚都能考到A3了 -天啊！
Hey! Even Abhigyan made it in A3. - Oh!
那邊的A3級學生有80%的可能性
The A3 students in over there have 80 percent probability..
考上印度理工
..of getting selected to JEE.
我不是故意參加考試的
I didn't mean to sit for the exam.
有什麼問題嗎？
What is the problem?
她冇通過也許是件好事
It's a good thing she did not make it.
怎麼個好法？
How is it good?
怎麼會好呢? 她坐在房間裏一定很傷心
How is it good? She must be very sad, sitting in room.
看到她難過，我會感到很難過
It will make me feel very bad to see her sad.
別管什麼英雄時刻了，我冇有勇氣去看她
Never mind the hero moment, I don't have the nerve to go see her.
你已經進入了 A1，但是你仍然保持著 A10的心態
You have made it to A1 but you have the same old A10 mentality.
有點遠見，不要總想著現在
Be a little foresighted. Don't think about the present.
想想未來
Think about the future.
聽著，如果她通過了，她就會去維吉安納加爾
Look, if she had made it, she would have gone to Vigyan Nagar.
而你被睏在這裏
You would be stuck in Talwandi.
你們每天要怎麼見麵？
How would you meet on a daily basis?
你來科塔已經四個月了，對吧？
It's been four months since you came to Kota, right?
你去過幾次維吉安納加爾？
How many times have you been to Vidyanagar?
我們可以摺中的地點見麵
We could meet midway somewhere.
當然，你每次都能去，但她又能來幾次
Sure, you would go. She wouldn't come time and again.
你很幸運
You were lucky.
看，現在你可以練習化學了
Look, now you can practice chemistry..
在這裏悠閒地度過一年
..in the streets of Talwandi at leisure through the year.
贏得她的芳心
Win her heart.
然後，你們就能像烏代所說的那樣了
Then if you wish you can do what Uday said as well.
該死！
Crap!
米納，你越來越聰明了
Meena, you have become very smart.
當然，我可不是無緣無故進入 A1的
Of course. I'm not in A1 without reason.
太棒了！
Wonderful!
怎麼樣，兄弟們？
What do you say, brothers?
可以吃蛋糕了嗎?-好的，當然
Shall we have cake? - Yes, yes. Of course.
-我已經七年冇吃蛋糕了-吃吧
It has been seven years since I had cake. - Eat.
教務處打來的電話
It's a call from the coaching class.
又冇到繳費的時間，他們為什麼現在打電話來？
We still have time to pay the fees. Why are they calling now?
你好
Hello.
什麼?-什麼？
What? - What?
我還以為你在難過-不，我冇事
I thought you'd be mourning. - No. I'm okay.
是的，當我看到麵包和果醬的時候我就知道了
Yes, I could tell when I saw the bread and jam.
但是，怎麼這麼冷靜？
But so chill?
你很放鬆，因為你的英雄通過了，對嗎？
You are relaxed because your hero made it, right?
聽著，我為他感到高興，但他不是英雄
Listen. I'm happy for him that he made it but he's no hero.
我真搞不懂你們
I've never understood you girls till date.
如果你喜歡這個男孩，那就去跟他錶白啊
If you like the boy, then go and propose to him.
就不，我們先偷偷地搞曖昧，然後等他來錶白
No. First we will romance secretly. Then we wait for him to propose.
然後我再考慮答不答應
Following which we shall think whether to say yes or no.
等一下，我為什麼要錶白？
Just a minute. Why should I propose?
你喜歡那個男孩?-你又開始那樣了
You like the boy? - You're back to that again.
去把這個交給瓦伊巴夫
Go and give this lecture to Vaibhav.
時代變了，姐妹，你喜歡的那種男人
Those times are gone, madam The kind of guy you like..
在你的情況下，你要嚮他錶白並且親吻他
..in your case you will have to propose and initiate the first kiss as well.
-說得好像你會跟烏代錶白似的?-我會的，我覺得冇問題
Like you proposed to Uday? - I would. I see no problem in it..
但我不需要，烏代可不是膽小鬼
..but I didn't need to. He isn't that pussy.
好吧，如果他是個膽小鬼，那就隨他去吧
Alright. If he is such a pussy then let it be.
你懷疑嗎? 不要懷疑了
You are in doubt? Don't remain doubtful.
他會答應的，他對你非常感興趣
He will say yes. He's highly interested.
烏代告訴你了？
Uday told you?
姐妹，你覺得為什麼《複活節快樂》這麼受歡迎？
Madam, why do you think Shivangi Renawat is so popular in 'Paschim Vihar"?
因為她能嗅到浪漫的氣息
Because she can sniff romance.
而且烏代也告訴了我
And Uday told me as well.
聽著，如果你願意，你可以採納我的建議，但我冇有強迫你
Look, you take my advice if you wish but there is no compulsion.
等等，烏代跟你說了什麼？
Listen. What did Uday say to you?
先生，我們冇有什麼特別的理由去參加考試
Sir, we didn't have any particular reason to sit for the exams.
六個小時，第一卷，第二卷，一共240道題
Six hours. Paper one. Paper two. 240 questions.
還說冇什麼特別的理由？
All of you sat for them for no particular reason?
真不錯！
Bravo!
是的，先生，我也冇有特別的理由
Yes, sir. Even I had no particular reason for it.
我們將與參加馬赫什瓦裏考試的同一批學生在JEE考試中競爭
We will be competing in JEE with the same students who sit for Maheshwari's test.
知己知彼，百戰不殆
Sir, one should know who one is competing with.
-這就是我去參加考試的原因 -俺也一樣
That's why I sat for it. - Yes, that is the correct reason.
我的意思是，這也是我的理由，先生
I mean to say that is my reason too, sir.
我也冇有其他特殊的原因
Even I sat for it without reason, sir.
你也是？
You too?
先生，他是故意去考的，他還提前30分鍾到達考場
Sir, he was deliberate. He reached there 30 minutes early.
而且他不是一個人去的，他還帶他妹妹參加了考試
And he did not go alone. He even got his sister to sit for the exam.
她不是我妹妹
She is not my sister.
你在想什麼，瓦伊巴夫·潘迪？
What were you thinking, Vaibhav Pandey?
我們優秀的學生都去參加了馬赫什瓦裏的入學考試
Our top students will go to sit for Maheshwari's entrance test..
而我們卻不知道？
..and we wouldn't know?
你到底有什麼問題？
What is your problem anyway?
為什麼不跟我說
You don't talk to me.
你們都是真正的天才
All of you are the real prodigies .
我們所有人都支持你
All of us are here for you.
我之前也說過，隻有A1組的學生都是我的強盜
I've said this earlier as well. A1 students are my rankers.
其他的學生都是我的提款機
The rest are my bankers.
我根本不在乎他們
I don't care about them.
告訴我，舒伯漢，你有什麼問題嗎？
Tell me, Shubham. What problem do you have here?
阿洛克？
Alok?
瓦伊巴夫？
Vaibhav?
神童的課程有什麼問題？
What is so wrong at Prodigy classes?
你們有什麼建議嗎？
Do you guys have any suggestions?
真的冇問題嗎？
You have no problem?
好吧，那你們告訴我那邊有什麼好的
Alright. Tell me what's good over there.
有嗎？
What is better over there?
聽著，無論你在這還是在那邊，都能考上
Look. You will be selected either here or there.
但在這裏，你們將成為最佳人選
But here you will be toppers.
還會得到一份獎品
You will receive a prize.
我們甚至為前十名支付了印度理工的學費
We even pay the IIT fees of the top ten rankers here.
我們做的市場營銷比他們多得多
We do far more marketing than them.
看看他
Look at him.
裏茹·加那
Rijul Jain.
他的全印度排名是19
His All India Rank was 19.
我們把這張臉貼滿了全城
We plastered his face all over the city.
給了他一輛寶馬
We gave him a BMW.
把他捧成了明星
We made him a star.
明星！
Star.
他18歲時收到了四份求婚書
He received four proposals at the age of 18.
這些都不能吸引你們嗎？
Is that a small feat?
他們會打印這麼大的照片嗎？
Will they print such big photos?
他們隻會印一個小的
They will print a tiny one.
聽著，孩子們，如果你們現在換培訓班，你們的日常生活就會受到影響
Look, boys. If you shift there now, your routine will suffer.
另外，他們隻會專註於從11年級
Plus they will focus on their toppers..
就入學的頂尖的學生
..who have been with them since the 11th grade.
我知道索梅什的弱點是S塊
Over here I know that Somesh is weak with S block.
瓦伊巴夫的平衡學的不好
Vaibhav's Equilibrium is haywire.
所以我會給你們補課
So I'll take extra classes.
給你們留作業
I'll give them practice question papers.
我會解決你們的疑惑
I will solve their doubts.
你們會在那邊能有這樣的待遇嗎? 告訴我
Are you going to receive such personal care over there? Tell me.
-能嗎?-不能，先生
Will you? - Yes, sir.
我明白，我不去
I understand. I won't go.
如果你們還有任何疑問的話，現在告訴我？
Ask me now if you have any doubts?
告訴我
Tell me.
大家都確定嗎?-是的，先生！
Is everyone sure? - Yes, sir!
我是說，我也是，哦不，我也不是，我不去，先生
I mean, me too, sir. Me neither, sir. Not going, sir.
你們付了12年級的學費嗎？
Did you pay the fees for 12th grade?
-還冇有，但我們會付的 -先生，我爸爸會付款的
No, sir. I have to. - Sir, dad will do so.
我們會付錢的，先生
It will be paid, sir.
We'll pay it, sir.
如果你還冇有付款，也冇關係，如果你已經付了，不用擔心
If haven't paid, it is okay and if you have paid it, don't worry.
我們會退款的
We will refund it.
A1組額外提供20% 獎學金
20 percent extra scholarships for the A1 batch.
如果你去那兒，你就得付更高的費用
If you go there you will have to pay higher fees..
而留在這裏我們給你發獎學金
..whereas we are giving you scholarships over here.
好嗎？
Okay?
好吧，把小冊子給他們
Fine. Give them the booklets.
還有我的電話號碼也給他們
Give all of them my number too.
我的個人號碼
My personal number.
還有問題嗎？
Okay?
好吧，解散
Well, alright. Dismiss.
- 謝謝，先生-謝謝，先生
Thank you, sir. - Thank you, sir.
對不起，先生
Sorry, sir.
你有他們所有人的名單，是嗎？
You have a list of all their names, don't you?
打電話給他們的父母
Call their parents.
我們幫助他們通過 NTSE，KVPY 和奧林匹克
We help them get through NTSE, KVPY and Olympiad..
然而這些白眼狼卻把他們的排名交給馬赫什瓦裏
..and the scoundrels will give their ranks to Maheshwari.
不用這麼緊張，先生
You are tense without reason, sir.
我跟他們談過了，他們哪兒也不會去
I've spoken to them. They won't go anywhere.
巴特拉先生，在培訓行業，這一年至關重要
Mr. Batla, in the coaching business it's all about one year only.
如果他們今年冇有拿到排名，我們明年就得不到入學許可了
If they don't get a rank this year we won't get admissions next year.
我們還要把他的照片掛多久？
How long will we print his photo anyway?
他看起來好醜
He looks so ugly.
是的，先生，真醜
Yes, sir. That is true.
但是，先生，如果你找一個孩子們都尊重的人去跟他們談
But, sir, when a respected man talks to the children..
-那他們一定會聽的-確實
..theydefinitely pay heed to him. -Correct.
叫傑圖先生和他們談談，他們會聽話的
Call Jeetu sir to talk to them. They will pay heed to him.
-他用了你的名字?-不僅如此
He took your name? - Not just my name.
他給了我這張卡片，上麵有他的個人號碼
He gave me this card with his personal number.
-他還給了我獎學金-給我看看
He even gave me scholarship. - Show me.
好好學習，否則你不會得到它
Work hard. You don't get it otherwise.
我打賭迪帕克看到這些尖子生要跳槽一定緊張的不行
I bet Deepak must have been sweating bullets seeing the toppers run.
是的，他對我們說話很有禮貌
Yes. He talked to us so politely...
我爸爸都冇跟我說話這麼客氣過
My dad never spoke to me so politely.
巴特拉是個感性的人
And Batla was so sentimental ..
他一定會升職的
He will surely get a promotion.
他說現在你在 A1，一切都會順利的
He said now that you are in A1 now it will be smooth sailing.
我們誤解了巴特拉
We have misunderstood Batla.
他甚至知道我的弱項
He even knows that I am weak at equilibrium.
他說會給我額外補課
He said I shall give you extra classes.
放棄馬赫什瓦裏，並留在神童的學生都贏得了尊重
Students who leave Maheshwari and remain with Prodigy gain respect.
我去年也放棄了馬赫什瓦裏，但是我冇有得到任何回報
I too left Maheshwari last year but I didn't gain any.
我應該重新參加考試嗎? 下一次考試是什麼時候？
Shall I reappear for the exams? When is the next exam?
現在有什麼好處，夥計？
What good will it do now, buddy?
優等生都已經考完了
The toppers already sat for the exam.
冇錯，反正他們也要開始新學期了
That's right. Their batches are going to begin anyway.
你可以明年參加
You can appear for it next year.
但是冇有人會真的過去
But nobody is going to go.
為什麼?-他們參加考試都隻是為了了解競爭情況
Why? - All of them sat for the exam only to check out the competition.
我們那麼努力才進入到A1組，為什麼現在要走？
We worked so hard to get to A1. Why would they go now?
是的，冇錯
Yes, that is correct.
嘿！索梅什
Hey, Somesh.
舒巴姆，我們在一起學習已經一年了
Shubham, we have been studying together for the past one year.
你從冇告訴過我你是比哈爾族人
You never told me you are a Bihari.
-不，我是來自格勒亨迪縣的奧裏亞族人 -我知道了
No, I am Oriya. From Kalahandi. - I see.
你的意思是你說話不像“我們正在做這件事”或“我們正在說那件事”
Do you mean you don't talk like "we are doing this" or "we are saying that?"
不是的
No.
那你他媽的為什麼在那裏亂說話？
Then why the fuck were you using those words over there?
我們之前就是這麼定的呀
That's what we decided we would say.
你這頭豬! 你應該說你不去的
You swine! You were supposed to say you aren't going.
但你說“我們” ，這不就說明我們已經串通好了嗎？
If you say "We", won't he know we have formed a group?
天知道什麼樣的白癡會去馬赫什瓦裏
Lord knows what kind of idiots make it to Maheshwari.
甜點給我
Give me dessert.
下次有人問你，你就說你不去
Next time anyone asks you say you aren't going.
如果他問起其他人，你就說你不知道
If he asks about the others, you say you don't know.
我冇跟任何人討論過這件事
I haven't spoken to anyone about it.
否則他們所有人都會追著我們不放
Else all of them will hound us.
我覺得巴特拉的話很有道理
I felt what Batla said made sense.
別聽他的，他在胡說八道！
Don't listen to him. He was talking nonsense!
你的S塊很差，那是因為他教得不好
You are weak at S block because he didn't teach it well.
巴特拉嫉妒我們，他自己都想去馬赫什瓦裏
Batla is jealous of us. He wants to go to Maheshwari himself..
但是馬赫什瓦裏不雇傭非印度理工畢業的教師
..but Maheshwari does not employ non-IITian teachers.
我們已經到了A1組，不是嗎？
We have made it to A1 somehow, haven't we?
-這不是也挺好的-在這裏任何白癡都能進A1組
We will deal with it. - Any idiot can make it to A1 over here.
你去馬赫什瓦裏考個A1我看看
Try getting into the A1 batch at Maheshwari.
它被稱為最好的學院不是冇有道理的
It is not known as the best institute without reason.
這裏的人JEE都考不好
These people cannot handle JEE.
而那邊的學生正在一個接一個地破解奧林匹克競賽題
Their students are cracking one Olympiad after another.
以後也是一樣，他們會跟你打感情牌
In future too they will lay it on thick with their emotional crap.
別理他，知道為什麼嗎？
Don't pay heed. You know why?
因為這裏有的，馬赫什瓦裏也有
Because they have several things at Maheshwari that are missing here..
因為這裏冇有的，馬赫什瓦裏也都有
..but they don't have anything over here that is missing at Maheshwari.
傑圖·拜亞？
Jeetu Bhaiya?
我不去，拜亞哥
I am not going, Bhaiya.
我已經開始學靜電學了
I have already started electrostatics.
那你為什麼還參加考試
Then why did you sit for the exam.
冇什麼
No reason.
我想看看我到底什麼水平
I wanted to see where I stand.
什麼水平? 你到 A1了嗎？
Did you see? Did you make it to A1?
我在 A3，但是我不去了，拜亞哥
I made it to A3. But I am not going, Bhaiya.
舒伯漢，你的朋友到底去不去？
Shubham, is your friend going or not?
拜亞哥，我不去，我也不知道他去不去
Bhaiya, I am not going. I don't know about him..
因為我們還冇討論過，我隻能告訴你我的計畫
..because we haven't discussed it. I can only tell you of my plans.
- 你們還冇討論過?-冇有
You haven't discussed it? - No.
你們是朋友，朋友之間應該討論一下的
You are friends. Friends should discuss things.
我們不是朋友，他都不知道我是奧裏亞族
We aren't friends, Bhaiya. He doesn't even know I am Oriya.
- 你來自格勒亨迪縣，對嗎?-是的，但我不去
From Kalahandi, right? - Yes. But I am not going.
冇錯，拜亞哥，我們也不去了
That's right, Bhaiya. Even we are not going.
好吧，那就冇什麼好說的了
Well, alright. There's no point then.
你們都走吧
All of you go. Chill.
拜亞哥
Bhaiya.
我聽到他們在餐廳裏聊天了
I heard both Shubham and Alok talking in the mess.
他們兩個都要去馬赫什瓦裏
Both of them are going to Maheshwari.
我可以給你書麵保證-我知道，這種事每年都會發生
I'd give you that in writing. - I know. It happens every year.
我也知道你不會去，但事實上你應該去
I also know that you aren't going, when in fact you should go.
每年我們這裏都有像你這樣的人
Every year we even have someone like you over here.
別說笑了，拜亞哥
Please stop ragging me, Bhaiya.
我是因為瓦蒂卡才去考試的
I only sat for the exam because Vartika..
我以後再跟你解釋，但是我不想去
I'll tell you later. But I don't want to go.
你去考試是件好事
You did a good thing by sitting for it.
既然你已經通過了，那你就應該去
Now that you have been selected you should go.
你可以好好學學物理學
Look, you can manage physics.
你的化學和數學都有待提高
You have a problem with chemistry and Math.
既然你已經放棄了化學
Now that you are giving up inorganic..
那就要加強數學和物理，不是嗎？
..you have to strengthen organic and physical, right?
那邊的老師教得更好
It is taught well over there.
但是我現在已經在這裏穩定下來了
But I am settled over here now, Bhaiya.
一切都很順利
Everything is going well.
我為什麼要現在離開？
Why would I leave now?
如果你不去，你要怎麼提升自己?
How will you grow if you don't go? Tell me.
俗話說得好，如果你是班上最聰明的人
You know the saying, if you're the smartest person in the class..
那你就進錯班了
..you're in the wrong class.
你在這裏和誰競爭？
With whom will you compete over here?
你所有的競爭對手都離開了
All your competition will leave.
舒伯漢姆和阿洛克，你們組的人都會離開的
Your batches, Shubham and Alok. All of them will leave.
與其在這裏得意洋洋地呆在 A1
Rather than getting complacent in A1 over here..
還不如在那邊的A3掙紮
..you'll be better off struggling in A3 over there.
考到那邊的 A1去
Make your way to A1 over there.
但是你在這裏，拜亞哥
But you are over here, Bhaiya.
你一次能愛上多少人？
How many people are you going to fall in love with at one time?
你不明白
You don't understand.
如果你想成長，你必須繼續前進
You must continue to move if you wish to grow.
如果你想聽我的講座，我每周都會上傳非學院的課程
If you want my lecture I give them on Unacademy plus every week.
你看重播就好了
Watch the live lecture on it.
魚和熊掌不可兼得
One has to give up on some things.
冇理由後悔
There's no reason to be remorseful.
我明白了
I see.
如果你的學生離開，你不會有挫敗感嗎
Won't you be hurt if one of your students leaves..
去另一個學院？
..to go to another Institute?
如果他不去，最後冇考上，我會更傷心
I will be hurt more if he doesn't go and he's not selected.
我們幫助你提高了一些，他們會讓你更上一層樓
We fixed some of your weaknesses and they will fix some.
對，你曾經說過，我不是一個人，我不應該緊張
Right. You told me I am not alone. I should not be nervous.
我們將一起攻克難關
We will crack IIT.
我們會一起戰鬥到最後一刻
We will fight together right up to the last minute.
我是在戰鬥啊
I am fighting.
你的選擇很重要
Your selection is important.
你在哪裏考上並不重要
Where you are selected from was never important.
怎麼了？
What's the matter?
拜亞哥，從我來這兒的第一天起
Bhaiya, from the first day that I arrived here..
我一直希望我的照片能掛在牆上
..it had been my wish to have my photo put up over here.
-他們也會把你的照片貼出來-不是那邊
So, they will put up your photo. - Not over there.
在這裏... 你所在的地方
Over here... The place where you are at.
聽著，阿瓊跟因陀羅學習，他也跟濕婆學習
Look, Arjun learned from Indra. He learned from Shiva too.
但他仍然被稱為德羅納的學生，不是嗎？
Still he was known as Dronacharya's student, wasn't he?
難道我不應該在名字前麵加上我以前的姓嗎？
Don't I put ex-Agarwalite in front of my name?
如果我是你，我會去的
If I were in your shoes I would go.
因為他們能讓你提升更多
Because we don't have anything here that they don't have over there.
你和瓦伊巴夫談過了嗎？
Have you spoken to Vaibhav?
冇有，我給他打了電話，但冇接通
No. I called him but I didn't get through.
我猜他一定在自習室，他會打電話來的
He must be at the Institute, I guess. He will call.
我和烏代談過了
I spoke to Uday.
瓦伊巴夫的教導主任找他談話了
Vaibhav's admin had summoned him..
還有其他要去馬赫什瓦裏的孩子一起
..along with the other kids who are going to Maheshwari.
他要去嗎?-不
He is going? - No.
我明白了，所以你才問我有冇有跟他談過
I see. That's why you asked me if I'd spoken to him.
交叉核對？
To cross check?
聽著，如果你叫他不要去，他一定不會去的
Listen. He won't go if you tell him not to go.
我為什麼不讓他去? 如果我是他的話，我會不去嗎？
Why should I tell him? Wouldn't I go if I were in his shoes?
這不就是我們參加考試的初衷嗎？
Wasn't that the reason we took the exam?
你完全冇有準備，他也冇有
For which you were not at all prepared and neither was he.
他甚至都不想參加考試
He didn't even want to sit for the exam.
然而整整一個星期，他把一切事情都放下了
Yet all week long he set everything aside..
來幫助你準備考試，對嗎？
..to help you prepare for the exam, right?
他本可以回家的，不是嗎? 然而他冇有回家
He could've gone home, couldn't he? He did not go.
因為他喜歡你，瓦蒂卡
Because he likes you, Vartika.
他喜歡你
He likes you.
如果你不想說，那就讓我和他談吧？
Do you want me to talk to him if you can't talk?
不要
Oh, no.
聽著，如果他去馬赫什瓦裏不是對他有好處嗎？
Look, won't it be good for him if he goes to Maheshwari?
-那邊什麼都有-冇有你
They have everything over there. - You aren't.
我這麼說不是為了你們的情愛浪漫
Look, I'm not saying this for the sake of your lovey-dovey romance.
我一點也不在乎那個
I couldn't give two hoots about that.
你們倆設定了一個目標
You two had set a goal that you were following.
他自學的效率絕對冇有你們一起學習的效率高
By himself he would never study as much as he studies with you.
你在一個星期內完成了11年級的全部教學大綱
You completed the entire syllabus of the 11th grade in one week..
你甚至都開始學習12年級的課程
..and you even started studying for 12th grade.
你以前有冇有提前學習過教學大綱? 冇有
Did you ever get ahead of the class syllabus before? No.
你並不是你們倆中唯一受益的人
You aren't the only one who will benefit by being together..
他也會從中受益
..he will also benefit.
他知道的，唯一的問題在於他不會告訴你
He knows this. The only problem is that he won't tell you.
那麼，你應該告訴他
So, you tell him.
你去幫他，別讓他一個人等著
You help him. Don't leave him hanging.
如果你有什麼問題，他會來幫助你的，不是嗎？
He will come to help you if you ever have a problem, won't he?
拜亞哥說的不對！
Jeetu bhaiya is wrong. Tell me.
你告訴我，他們那邊有什麼？
You tell me. What do they have over there?
他們那邊A3組有80%能考上
80 percent of the A3 batch from Maheshwariis selected, right?
還有20%考不上，拜亞哥冇有告訴你嗎？
20 percent does not get selected. Jeetu Bhaiya didn't tell you that.
你不按時起床上課，每天我都來叫醒你
You don't wake up on time for classes. I wake you up.
你一個人在那邊怎麼辦？
How will you prepare on your own over there?
拜亞哥冇有告訴你，你們討論過這個嗎？
Jeetu Bhaiya didn't tell you that. Did you discuss this?
我們冇有聊那麼細
He was only discussing with me.
再說我們會保持聯係的
Besides, we will stay in touch, Meena.
你為什麼這麼說？
Why are you saying such things?
真的? 你見過皮尤什嗎？
Really? Do you meet Piyush?
他是你學校的朋友，不是嗎？
He was your school friend, wasn't he?
告訴我這幾個月你有去看過他嗎？
Tell me how many times you went to see him in all these months.
一旦你去了那裏，你就冇有時間聯係我了
Once you go there you won't have the time.
還有，你欠我七個泡芙
Also, you owe me seven puffs.
你不給我就不能走
You can't leave until you give it to me.
就這麼定了，你不能走
That is final. That is final.
我還在思考這個問題
I am still pondering over it.
我還不知道
I don't know as yet.
迪帕克說一套，拜亞哥又說一套
Deepak is saying something. Bhaiya is saying something else.
-我不知道我該怎麼辦-看到了嗎？
I don't know what I should do. - You see?
看到了嗎? 看到了嗎？
You see? You see?
我才是那個給你指點迷津的人
I am the one who explains everything to you.
冇有我，你就冇辦法理解
Without me you cannot make sense of things.
你跟他說說，烏代，我也去跟他說
You talk to him, Uday. I'll talk to him too.
你不能去，好嗎？
You are not going. Okay?
你告訴他，烏代
You tell him, Uday.
-我能說什麼呢?-告訴他不要去
What can I say? - Tell him not to go.
你我說什麼對他來說都不重要
What you or I say shouldn't matter to him.
他來這裏的目的是考上印度理工學院
He came here to prepare for IIT.
不是嗎？
Didn't you?
所以，你去吧
So, do that.
我想現在我們覺得來到了科塔，我們玩得很開心
I guess right now we feel we have come to Kota, we are having fun..
我們一起學習
..we are going out, studying,
創造美好的回憶
memories are being created..
並且建立友誼
..and forming friendships..
但是如果我們在這一切結束時，得不到想要的結果
..but if we don't get the desired result at the end of all this..
那樣我們就不會回想起這些時光了
..then we won't feel like turning around and remembering these times.
那麼它就會作為不好的記憶，留在我們的腦海裏
Then it stays with us as a bad memory.
如果冇考上，那些被我們浪費掉的時間就會一直睏擾著我們
If we aren't selected then all our mischief will haunt us as mistakes.
我們都是同齡人
We are at such an age.
無法預見未來
We are unable to foresee the future.
你還在猶豫，是嗎？
You are in doubt, aren't you?
-和你爸爸談談-就好像你很聽你爸的話一樣
Talk to your dad. - As though you pay heed to your dad.
我不能聽從他的指示
I am unable to follow his instructions.
這並不意味著我無視他的看法
It does not mean that I don't pay heed to him.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我無法集中註意力，我不能像你們這樣坐6個小時
I am unable to concentrate. I cannot sit up 6 hours like you guys.
我該怎麼辦？
What should I do?
你告訴我，米納，我該怎麼辦？
You tell me, Meena. What should I do?
告訴我，我是應該跳樓還是上吊，或者直接離家出走
Tell me. Shall I leap to death, hang or run away?
我回不去了
I can't even return.
人們會問我發生了什麼
People will ask me what happened.
你想考印度理工學院，但是冇考上？
You wanted to join IIT. You didn't get selected into IIT?
我看著你的時候覺得很慚愧，米納
I feel ashamed of myself when I look at you, Meena.
盡管你家境不好，我還是為你的成就而感到羞愧
I feel ashamed of your achievements despite your background.
我什麼都有了
I have everything.
盡管擁有了一切，但我卻一事無成
Despite having everything I failed to achieve anything.
我什麼也做不了
I am unable to do anything.
我父親是國稅局官員
My father is an IRS Officer.
我該怎麼跟他說我是廢物？
How do I tell him I am worthless?
我考不上印度理工學院
I won't be able to crack the IIT exams.
請原諒我！
Please pardon me!
我該怎麼告訴他，米納？
How do I tell him, Meena?
和你爸爸談談
Talk to your dad.
他叫你做什麼你就做什麼
Do what he tells you to do.
你父母的決定可能是錯誤的
Your parents' decision could be wrong..
但他們的意圖絕不會錯
..but their intent is never wrong.
我們要把這個物體從位置 a 帶到位置 b
We have to take this object from location A to location B.
對不對？
Correct?
它不會僅僅靠吹氣就到那裏去
It won't go there just by blowing.
它需要被推動
It needs to be pushed.
這個物體需要一個推力，就像每個人都需要一個推力
This object needs a push like every person needs a push.
所以我們要對它施加力量
So we shall apply force toit.
我們隻施加足夠的力把它推到中性點
We only apply enough force to push it to the neutral point.
它自身的潛力將帶領它走完剩下的路程
Its own potential will take it the rest of the way.
對嗎? 關於這個問題我已經告訴你很多了
Correct? I've told you a lot about this problem.
你來解決剩下的問題，然後下節課我們再來討論
You solve the rest of it and bring it back to the next class.
我們下次什麼時候見麵？
When will we be meeting next?
我們什麼時候見麵? 星期四，所以，你有兩天時間
When will we meet? On Thursday. So, you have two days.
在那之前，先解決問題
Until then, solve the problem.
坐，坐，怎麼了？
Sit. Sit. What is the matter?
你決定了嗎？
Have you decided?
這是給你的
This is for you.
給我的？
For me?
謝謝你所做的一切
Thank you for everything.
哇，大手筆！
Oh big spender!
如果你在我身上花了這麼多錢，那個考試的女孩叫什麼名字？
If you are spending so much on me, what is the name of the exam girl?
你一定花了不少錢在瓦妮莎身上
You must have really splurged on the Vernali.
瓦蒂卡-你同時勾引兩個女孩？
Vartika. - You are hitting on two girls simultaneously?
別鬨了，拜亞哥
Just drop it, Bhaiya.
來，我給你看樣東西
Come. I'll show you something.
過來，過來
Come. Come.
這邊
Over here.
你進來怎麼不脫鞋，算了，進來吧
You will take off your shoes..? leave it just come in.
你看到這些了嗎？
Do you see these?
這是阿瑪尼的
This is Armani.
這是古馳的
This is Gucci.
我覺得這個在印度都買不到
I think this one isn't even available in India.
看到那雙鞋了嗎？
You see those shoes?
LV的
All of them are LV.
這些手錶，雷多，勞力士
These watches. Rado. Rolex.
沙魯克為這個做的廣告
Shahrukh does the ad for this one.
我一直想搞清楚這句法語是什麼意思
I wonder what's written here in French.
你為什麼要炫耀這些，拜亞哥？
Why are you showing off, Bhaiya?
我必須炫耀，這些都是我學生送的禮物
I have to. These are gifts from my students.
這才是我真正的收入
This is my true earning.
我從不穿這些，但我穿起來最好看
I don't wear them but I look best in them.
來自印度理工學院孟買分校的沙佈哈姆，然後去了麻省理工學院
Shubham from IIT Bombay. Then MIT.
這是印度理工的阿卡什送的，後來他輟學
This is from Akash. IIT Kanpur. CS dropout.
去了微軟
Then Microsoft.
他現在有一家創業公司，天知道他以後還會做什麼
He has a startup now. Lord knows what he's going to do.
那是奇拉格送的
That's from Chirag.
這是來自詹維的
This is from Jhanvi.
他們和你一樣，都給我送了禮物
Like you, all of them had brought gifts for me.
我都冇有接受
I didn't accept.
我不反對禮物，我接受禮物
Nothing against gifts. I do accept gifts..
隻要是用你自己的收入買來的就行
..as long as they're bought with your earning..
用你父親的收入可不算
..not with your father's earning.
努力學習，完成你的學業
Work hard. Complete your studies.
在你成功之後
And after you become successful..
如果你還記得有人叫傑圖·拜亞或傑圖先生
..if you still remember anyone called Jeetu Bhaiya or Jeetu sir..
那時候你再來給我送一份禮物，我就會接受它
..then you bring me a gift. Then I shall accept it.
我不接受這麼便宜的東西
And I don't accept such cheap stuff.
你留著吧
Keep it.
好好保管，好好利用它
Take care of it. Make good use of it..
然後去馬赫什瓦裏
..and go to Maheshwari.
好嗎？
Okay?
是或不是，說點什麼，兄弟
Yes or no. Say something, bro.
去吧
Go.
瓦蒂卡冇來嗎？
Didn't Vartika come?
你冇有打電話叫她來嗎？
Did you call and ask her to come?
姐妹
Man.
我冇法給她打電話
I couldn't get myself to call her.
你能幫我做件事嗎? 你能把這些筆記給她嗎？
Will you do something for me? Will you please give her these notes?
為什麼？
Why?
你不能給她嗎？
Can't you give them to her?
天知道我什麼時候能見到她-不關我的事
Lord knows when I'll see her. - Not my problem.
你自己給她吧
Give them to her yourself.
還有東西嗎?-冇有了
Any more bags? - No.
保重
Well, take care.
保持聯係
Stay in touch.
我把延長線放在你的包裏了
I put the extension cord in your bag.
他要價150盧比，別給他超過100盧比
He is demanding 150 rupees. Don't give him more than 100.
米納
Meena.
七個洋蔥泡芙
Seven onion puffs.
我欠你的，不是嗎？
I owed you, didn't I?
我在離開之前要清算一下比分
I am clearing the score before leaving.
-拿著-不，你留著吧
Take it. - No, no. You keep it.
等你到了那邊食堂就關門了，吃這個吧
The mess won't be open when you get there. Eat this.
你拒絕吃洋蔥泡芙？
You are refusing onion puffs?
我不會放過你的
I am not letting you off the hook.
我在印度理工等你
Meet me at IIT.
到那裏再清算
Repay me there.
那邊冇有賣這個的，所以你得付很高的利息
This won't be available over there, so, you'll have to pay heavy interest.
你得用羊角麵包付賬-我明白了
You'll have to pay with croissants. - I see.
到時候我會在理工學院幫你解題
When I solve your doubts in IIT..
你得付我雙倍的羊角麵包
..you will have to pay me with double the number of croissants.
明白了嗎?-你能幫我解題嗎？
Get it? - You will solve my doubts?
走著瞧-走著瞧
We shall see. - We shall see.
你想賭一把嗎?-賭一把
You wanna bet on it? - It's a bet.
-我們保持聯係-不不
We shall stay in touch. - No, no.
你好好學習，不要去想這些
You study. Don't think about it.
無論如何，住在一起和偶爾見麵
In any case, there's a difference between meeting sometimes..
還是有區別的
..and living together.
說到底，在這條路上，友誼不是必須的
Anyway friendship is not revision that must be done.
專註於你的學業
Focus on your studies.
再見
Bye.
再見，兄弟
See you, bro.
再見
Bye.
請代我嚮瓦蒂卡說再見
Please say bye to Vartika for me.
雙層羊角麵包
Double croissants.
瓦伊巴夫！
Vaibhav!
等我一下，兄弟
Stop for a minute, brother.
怎麼了? 冇事吧？
What's the matter? Is everything okay?
冇事，我一路跑過來的
Yes, I ran over.
這就是為什麼……-哦
That's why.. - Oh.
我以為你明天早上才走
I thought you were leaving tomorrow morning.
是的，實際上新來的租客讓我今天把房間空出來，所以……
Yes. Actually the new PG told me to shift today, so..
哦
Oh.
對不起
Sorry.
我應該給你打電話的
I should have called you.
我冇想到你會離開
I didn't think you would leave.
我們很合得來
We clicked well.
- 我們一起學習-是的
With our studies. - Yes.
我是說……
I mean..
其實我也冇想到我會去
Actually even I did not think I would go..
但我必須要去了
..but I have to go.
好吧
Yes.
這是給你的
This is for you.
這對你會有所幫助
It will be useful to you.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你冷嗎？
Are you cold?
不冷，怎麼了？
No. Why? What happened?
你在發抖，所以我才問的
You are shivering. That's why I asked.
是的
Yes.
我不知道，也許吧
I don't know. Maybe.
我想這是因為我有點緊張
I guess it is happening because I am a little nervous.
哦！
Oh!
等等，拿著這個
Wait a minute. Hold this.
-幹嘛?-拿著
What's the matter? - Hold it.
張嘴
Have this.
謝謝
Thanks.
剩下的酸奶怎麼辦？
What will you do with the rest of the yogurt?
別擔心，我會把它塗在頭髮上
Don't worry. I'll apply it on my hair.
惡心死了！
Gross! Yuck!
祝你順利考上理工學院
Best of luck for IIT.
為了理工學院
For IIT.
再見
See you.
會再見的
You will.
我是瓦伊巴夫
'This is Vaibhav.'
“是的”
'Yes.'
這是我的科塔好嗎，存一下吧
'This is my Kota number. Save it.'
“不，不是在馬赫什瓦裏，我在神童”
'No, not in Maheshwari. Prodigy.'
“我是米納，神童A5組”
'I am Meena. Prodigy. A5.'
你為什麼不早點來科塔
'Why didn't you come to Kota earlier?'
“我們本可以早點成為朋友”
'We would have become friends earlier.'
你好，瓦伊巴夫，你來自伊塔爾西，來到了神童
'Hi. Vaibhav. You're from Itarsi. You have come to Prodigy.'
“你就像阿姨的兒子，對吧? ”
'You are like a son to aunty, right?'
像你這樣一個脆弱無助的孩子
'What is the reason a fragile and helpless boy like you..
在學期中途離開家，拋棄一切來到了科塔
..left his home, school and all else mid semester to come to Kota?'
’你遲到了，所以有些落後
'You are lagging behind because you are late..
但你並不孤單
..but you aren't alone.'
“我們將戰鬥到最後一刻，考上理工學院”
'We will fight right up to the last minute and crack IIT.'
是的
'Yes!'
你有火柴嗎？
Do you have a match box?
不，不是為了點煙
No. Not to light a cigarette.
我想點蚊香
I want to light a mosquito coil.
這裏有很多蚊子
There are many mosquitoes here.
應該有，我找找看
Yes, I might have one. Let me see.
我可以進來嗎？
May I come in?
我是蘇什塔，馬赫什瓦裏，A7組
I am Sushrut. Maheshwari classes. A7.
我住在樓上的房間，昨天搬進來的
I stay in the room upstairs. I moved in yesterday.
你呢？
You?
瓦伊巴夫，馬赫什瓦裏，A3組
Vaibhav. Maheshwari. A3.
那麼，這是你的第一年還是你以前參加過培訓班？
So, is this your first year or did you attend coaching before?
我11年級的時候在神童教育
I was in Prodigy in the 11th grade.
-塔爾萬迪-哦！
Talwandi. - Oh.
那你一定是個書呆子
Then you must be quite a bookworm.
也不是，我每天也就五六個小時是書呆子
No. The usual five to six hours types.
我才剛來
I have only just come.
每個人都使我大吃一驚
Seeing everyone has shaken me up.
我真希望我是來上11年級的
I wish I had come for the 11th grade.
我覺得12年級有點來不及了
I think 12th grade is a little late.
今年我也要寄宿在這裏
I have my boards too this year.
完全不知道該怎麼辦
I wonder how I will manage.
不要緊張
Don't be tense.
隻需21天
Only 21 days.
你隻需要勤奮學習21天
You just have to slog for 21 days.
之後你就會習慣了
After that you will blend in.
要來點泡芙嗎？
You want some puffs?